guess who's back that's right back again
with another adjustable dumbbell review
adjustable dumbbells are the ideal
solution for anybody who's tied on space
or maybe working with a tight budget but
you know wants to add some dumbbells to
their home gym now I've reviewed a
handful of adjustable dumbbells for you
all by now but I've been using the
NordicTrack select away adjustable
dumbbells a whole lot lately so let's go
ahead and break down my experience
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake and for
today's video I've got a pair of Nordic
tracks select away adjustable dumbbells
in the barbing garage gym for review now
in this video I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about these
dumbbells from the price to the features
some pros and cons you may experience
while working out with them but most
importantly who should or maybe should
not buy these now before I get going
with all of that I gotta let you know
we've reviewed a ton of adjustable
dumbbells on barbin.com so I think you
should definitely go ahead and search
barbend best adjustable dumbbells that
way you can find out for yourself which
ones that we like the best
Okay so let's talk about what I like
about these dumbbells I want to talk
about the construction first so
NordicTrack actually redesigned these
dumbbells and I'm pretty pumped about it
so now you have a steel handle and it
does have a moderate knurling so it's
going to help you out and give you a
pretty solid grip also like how you can
adjust the weight it's pretty easy to do
it you have these pins right here on on
both sides of the dumbbell all you have
to do is pull up you know select where
you want it to go and you're good to go
that's why they're called select awaits
but you also have some two and a half
pound increments that you can work with
and to do that you have these pins on
the inside right here of the Dumbo heads
all you do is pull up slide it where you
want it to go and you're good to go it's
pretty simple and we like simple these
are also going to replace 15 individual
dumbbells at a fraction of the footprint
you know these range from 10 to 55
pounds that's a pretty solid range these
are also available for right around 350
bucks and that's you know significantly
cheaper than what a full set of
dumbbells is going to cost you but these
are also some of the most affordable
adjustable dumbbells on the market which
honestly is a bargain considering the
quality here they're you know they're
obviously going to be bigger than a
traditional dumbbell they kind of have
to be you know with the adjustment
mechanisms and everything like that but
you know they're not that big you know
compared to some other adjustable
dumbbells on the market which is
honestly pretty nice you're not going to
really have to change your movements
during your exercises which is a pretty
nice thing right there you're also going
to receive a free month of iFit with
your purchase and if you don't know what
iFit is well you might want to take some
notes and pay attention because there's
over 16
000 classes for you to join at any given
moment so if you have any NordicTrack
cardio equipment stream these classes
directly from that monitor or you can
download the companion app and do so
from your phone at any moment of the day
now you are going to have to pay about
40 bucks a month for that membership
afterwards but it's pretty cool you do
get a free month
okay so there aren't too many cons in my
opinion with these dumbbells but there's
still a few you might run into so let's
go ahead and talk about that I want to
talk about the max weight first so 55
pounds might be solid for a lot of you
watching it might be enough weight it's
going to be pretty solid as well for
some accessory work but you know there's
plenty of people out there that 55
pounds is just simply not going to get
the job done so if that's you you know
if that's the case for you I suggest
checking out some heavier options
there's some that can go as heavy as 90
pounds those are also going to be a lot
more expensive there's not a whole lot
of plastic used here but you know this
adjustment pin and then on the inside of
the weight plates it's also plastic
right there so over time you know that
might wear down on you and you know
might cause everything to stick or maybe
not you know walk in place that great I
don't think you have to worry about it
for a while but you know later on down
the road that might be a cause for
concern
the handles are not ergonomically shaped
which I personally am totally fine with
that I don't really care for my
dumbbells to have an ergonomic handle
but you know some people like them being
thicker in the middle and if that's you
you know I also suggest checking out
some other options that are online and
lastly is the shape of the actual
dumbbell heads so as you can see these
are pretty rounded and I personally like
using dumbbells for push-ups because it
keeps my wrist in a neutral position but
that's something you're really not going
to be able to do with these
all right so let's break down the money
a little bit more now the Nordic Track
select away adjustable dumbbells are
available for right around 350 bucks
which is honestly a really solid deal
these are the most affordable adjustable
dumbbells I've reviewed lately and you
know that's not to take away from the
quality because once I unbox these I was
actually really impressed with how they
felt and really just overall appearance
of them the pictures online in my
opinion don't really do these Justice
now if you want to finance this purchase
NordicTrack is absolutely going to allow
you to do so in two different ways so
you can make monthly payments of about
10 bucks a month for 39 months or you
can pay around 30 bucks a month for a
year either way you know it just goes to
show that these are ridiculously
affordable in my opinion there aren't
that many options out there that are
cheaper than these but there's plenty
that are more expensive you know some
are going to run you around nine hundred
dollars and considering the quality here
is not that far off this is a great
option for anyone looking to save some
money
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with these
adjustable dumbbells I want to talk
about the handles first I like how
they're steel I'm not 100 positive about
the handle diameter but it seems to be
about 30 millimeters which is you know
pretty nice they also do have a moderate
knurling which is going to help you out
a lot in terms of getting a solid grip
as you're working out the plates are in
fact made of steel there's not a whole
lot of plastic used here but you know
there is some in the middle and that's
really with this adjustment mechanism
the pin I don't really think you have to
worry about that for a really long time
but you know it's plastic so you never
really know your storage trays here are
in fact made of plastic and you know in
terms of Dimensions they're about 19 and
a half inches long roughly 11 and a half
inches wide and including the dumbbells
you know when they're stored about eight
and a half inches tall so you know
obviously that's not a whole lot of
space these are going to require and so
that's really nice you know you can
slide these under underneath your bed
you can put them in a closet you know
stash them in the corner of a room
really whatever you know this is a
really nice touch you also have a weight
chart right here on the trays which is
extremely helpful and NordicTrack is
also going to toss in a 90-day warranty
covering any manufacturing defects that
you may experience
[Music]
all right so let's go ahead and break
these down up close and just show you
how to adjust the weight so I really
like these handles right here as I've
mentioned a couple times you know I
really like the steel also like the
knurling it's going to give you a really
solid grip as you're working out but as
you can see you know that is not
ergonomically shaped so you know it's
the same diameter all the way across
which is right around 30 millimeters or
so which is pretty solid there's not a
ton of plastic used here still the
presence has definitely felt you know
with the adjustment pins and on the
inside of the steel plates right here
that's also plastic now to adjust the
weight it's pretty easy just pull up on
this pin and slide you know wherever you
want it to go do it on both sides or
else it's going to be lopsided you don't
want that but it's a really simple
process it's really you know easy to do
it I really like the weight chart right
here on the tray you know that's just
going to be really helpful as you you
know go to adjust the weight and you
always know how much weight you're
lifting now you do have some two and a
half pound increments with these
dumbbells and that's really nice when
with dumbbells because you know not
everybody likes making that five pound
jump with all of their dumbbell
exercises so to do that you're going to
slide this pin right here in the front
and so each of these plates right here
weigh one and a half pounds so when the
pin is slid all the way over here as you
see we have everything so that's adding
five pounds depends in the middle you're
not to have any of them and then when
you adjust the pin all the way over here
you know you're gonna be working with
two and a half pounds and lastly you
know as you see these heads are rounded
so I like using dumbbells for push-ups
but you know with these it's something
you really don't want to be doing
okay so when it comes to the people who
might want to purchase these adjustable
dumbbells this is technically a two for
one right here so if you are tight on
space and you don't necessarily want to
break the bank for a quality pair of
adjustable dumbbells you really might
want to strongly consider scooping these
bad boys up 350 is a really solid price
these are going to replace 15 individual
dumbbells and overall they're just
pretty high quality in my opinion and
also you know if you don't need more
than 55 pounds of weight then these are
going to be a really solid option for
you to consider
[Music]
and when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase these dumbbells we need
to talk about the max weight first so 55
pounds is probably going to be plenty of
enough weight for you know some bicep
curls some overhead tricep extensions
some front and lateral raises maybe some
split squats you know all that stuff but
when it comes to doing a dumbbell bench
press maybe some shoulder presses that
might not be enough weight for everybody
so if you do in fact need more than 55
pounds of weight well I definitely
suggest checking out some other
adjustable dumbbells that offer more
weight just remember those are going to
be a lot more expensive other than that
though I think it really just boils down
to personal preference on the overall
design of the dumbbells you know that's
including the handles maybe you don't
like the lack of an ergonomic design if
you don't like the knurling maybe you
don't like the way you adjust the weight
you know if you're not crazy about those
features then I suggest just checking
out some other options
well that's all I have for you guys
today on the NordicTrack select away
adjustable dumbbells I've honestly been
thoroughly impressed by these dumbbells
since the day I got them I don't really
see that changing anytime soon they're
extremely affordable it's really easy to
adjust the weight they're going to
replace 15 individual dumbbells and also
really like the knurling on the steel
handles really the only downside in my
opinion is that they cap out at 55
pounds so if you need heavier dumbbells
than that you're gonna have to keep
looking thanks for watching everybody I
hope this video was really helpful and
that I was able to break down everything
there is to know about these adjustable
dumbbells as always stay posted for my
next video but for now you should
definitely head over to barbin.com to
read more about this product all you got
to do is search bar Bend NordicTrack
select await dumbbells review and you'll
find all the details and everything that
we talked about here today I'll catch
y'all later
[Music]
foreign